Bauchwitz, Kurt (Roy C. Bates); Papers ger011
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence Files, 1914-1987; 2; 1 Digital Files 429 file folders
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1941-1974; 2.5; 117 file folders
    - Guillemin, Roger, 1970 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 78)
      2 letters from, 1 letter to; 1 cl.
    - Gutman, J., 1957 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 79)
    - Herbig (Müller), Elfriede, 1967-1968 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 80)
      1 letter to, 5 related letters.
    - Horowitz, David, 1950 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 81)
    - Housing, Undated (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 82)
      Miscellaneous correspondence, dealing with housing and household matters, incl. purchase and repairs, 1947-1974: 28 letters by R.C.Bates (Barbara), 16 replies; also documents concerning the purchase of a house at 996 Canton Avenue, Milton, Massachusetts, 1961-1962. 8 items; real estate tax records.
    - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 83)
    - Humphreys, Christmas (The Buddhist Society), 1965 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 84)
      1 letter from, 1 letter to; summer school advertisements.
    - Jacob, Erich, [1964] (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 85)
      1 card from.
    - Javits, Jacob J., 1947 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 86)
    - Lawrence, C. H., 1942 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 87)
    - Levy, Karen, 1972 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 88)
    - Lewin, Bertram D., 1950 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 89)
    - Libraries and museums, 1942-1968; 18 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 90)
    - Maine. Correspondence, 1947; 1960; 1961 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 91)
      re: vacation plans, primarily letters dealing with accommodations, accompanied by brochures, rate schedule; notes, planned itineraries.
    - Manso, Leo, 1946 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 92)
    - Massachusetts Historical Society, 1966 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 93)
    - McPharlin, Paul, 1947 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 94)
    - Medical services (Roy C. Bates), 1944-1978; ca. 35 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 95)
      Correspondence, copies of bills, medicare payments, etc.
    - Medical / Retirement (Barbara Bates), 1969-1972; ca. 55 items (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 96)
      Correspondence concerning retirement and health insurance benefits, primarily with the Boston Retirement Board, Boston Teachers Union, and Blue Cross - Blue Shield.
      notes.
    - Milton, Massachusetts, 1961 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 97)
      2 letters to town officials.
    - Montagu, Ashley, 1966 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 98)
    - Musial, S.?, 1939 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 99)
    - Nichols, Brigitte, 1948 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 100)
    - O'Kearsey, Mary E., 1974 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 101)
    - Perthes, Justus (Geographisches Verlagsanstalt), 1968 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 102)
    - Pets. Miscellaneous correspondence, records, 1961-1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 103)
      5 items, l cl.
    - Rasmusses Jr., Arthur, 1964 (Box 6 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 104)
    - Reiff, Reverend Karl, 1940-1974 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 1)
      14 letters, cards from, 9 letters to; miscellaneous cl. and materials. 8 items.
    - Richter-Uhlitzsch, Charlotte, 1946-1947 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 2)
    - Saphier, James L. ("Somebody Knows"), 1950 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 3)
      2 letters from, 1 letters to.
    - Sastri, K. A. Nilakanta, 1959-1960 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 4)
    - Satterfield, Elaine, 1958-1959 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 5)
    - Scott, Walter (Parade), 1968 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 6)
    - Selver (Brooks), Charlotte, 1967 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 7)
      2 letters from, 2 letters to; seminar advertisements.
    - Silent Unity, 1941 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 8)
    - Smith, Alvin W, 1948 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 9)
    - Snead, Stella, 1946; Undated (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 10)
      1 letter, 1 card from.
    - Spalek, John M. Correspondence with Barbara Bates, 1974-1982 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 11)
      8 letters from, 8 letters to.
    - Stebbins, Henry E. (Ambassador), 1966 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 12)
      3 letters, card from, 2 letters to; 1 cl.
    - Stern, Tania, 1967 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 13)
    - Suzuki, Daisetz T., 1950 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 14)
      1 letter from, 2 letters to; notes.
    - Swenson, Elaine, 1941 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 15)
    - Todd, Charles L. (Department of State), 1952 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 16)
      Correspondence and proposals concerning an Overseas Information Program.
      1 letter from, 3 letters to; diary entries describing two meetings between R.C.B. and Todd; proposals by R.C.B. ca. 15p.; notes and cl.
    - Trencher, Carol, 1951 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 17)
      3 letters from, 3 letters to.
    - Truman, Harry S., 1947 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 18)
    - Udomo, Udo, 1966 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 19)
      1 letter, 1 card from; 1 cl.
    - Vaughan, Martha, 1961; Undated (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 20)
      1 card from, 1 letter to.
    - The Viking Fund, Inc. (Paul Fejos), 1950 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 21)
    - Wagenhöfer, Kay. 1 card with note from, Undated (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 22)
    - Watts, Alan, 1962 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 23)
      2 letters from, 1 letter to, 1 related letter.
    - Weinberg, Alice and Erich, 1951 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 24)
    - Westover, James (WEEI), 1961 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 25)
    - Wheeler, Erma, 1963 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 26)
    - Wohlgemuth, Ferdinand, 1941 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 27)
    - Woodruff, Ruth, 1974 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 28)
    - The World Publishing Company, 1967 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 29)
    - Wyckoff, D. Campbell (The Templeton Prizes), 1961 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 30)
    - Zogbaum, Margaret, 1957-1965 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 31)
    - Zozo, Carol, 1972 (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1947-1970; ca. 40 items (Box 7 (2-Correspondence Files), Folder 33)
- Manuscripts and Typescripts, 1928-1977; 3; 209 file folders
  The manuscripts and typescripts are divided into two sub-series: poetry, epigrammatic verse and aphorisms make up the first, while prose writings comprise the second sub-series.
  - Poetry, Epigrammatic Verse, Aphorisms, 1928-1977; 3.1; 115 file folders
    This sub-series is arranged chronologically by groupings/collections of poetry and epigrammatic verse, and chronologically within each grouping. Main groupings include: Der Lebendige, "Abzieh-Bilderbuch", "Tokyo poems", "Einsätze/Monogriphs", "Gedichte", "Versepigramme", "Silben: Haiku und tanka", "Ego and Echo", and "Der Zitronenbaum". With the exception of the "Monogriphs" and AEgo and Echo" collections, which are in English, the majority of the poems, epigrams and aphorisms are in German.
    - Der Lebendige, Undated; 3.1.1 (Box 7 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 34-37)
      - Typescripts of selected poems from the published volume, 72p (Box 7 (3.1.1-Der Lebendige), Folder 34)
      - Photocopied pages from the volume, with indications (from Barbara Bates) for poems to be typed, 72p (Box 7 (3.1.1-Der Lebendige), Folder 35)
      - Photocopied pages from the volume, with indications (from Barbara Bates) for poems to be typed, 47p (Box 7 (3.1.1-Der Lebendige), Folder 36)
        Notes from Barbara Bates. Autograph 3p.
      - Typescripts of selected poems from the volume, most pages coded with "DL" in upper left corner, 78p (Box 7 (3.1.1-Der Lebendige), Folder 37)
    - Poems, aphorisms, short prose, diary entries, 1928-1938; 3.1.2 (Box 7 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 38-41)
      Pages removed from notebook labeled "Leitz I". Contains a mixture of original typescripts and carbons with h. corrections, with some duplicate pages. Also a few handwritten pages. Although many of the items are dated, the pages are not arranged in chronological order, but are hand-numbered 1-747. Items in one section, pp. 231-611, have been individually hand-numbered from 1180-2405.
      - Pages 1-200 (Box 7 (3.1.2-Poems, aphorisms, short prose, diary entries), Folder 38)
      - Pages 201-400 (Box 7 (3.1.2-Poems, aphorisms, short prose, diary entries), Folder 39)
      - Pages 401-599 (Box 7 (3.1.2-Poems, aphorisms, short prose, diary entries), Folder 40)
      - Pages 600-747 (Box 7 (3.1.2-Poems, aphorisms, short prose, diary entries), Folder 41)
    - Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose, 1927-1938; 3.1.3 (Box 7 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 42-44)
      (with the exception of three items, with pencilled dates of 1904, 1905, 1920) (all located in folder 42). Pages removed from an unlabeled Leitz notebook are a mixture of original typescripts and carbons with h. corrections. Although many items are dated, the pages are not arranged in chronological order, nor are they numbered. Items in the last section, pp. 419-709, have been individually hand-numbered from 1-905 (folder 44), dated mainly 1934-1935.
      - Pages 1-199 (Box 7 (3.1.3-Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose), Folder 42)
      - Pages 200-418 (Box 7 (3.1.3-Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose), Folder 43)
      - Pages 419-709 (Box 7 (3.1.3-Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose), Folder 44)
    - Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose, 1930-1938; 3.1.4 (Box 7 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 45-47)
      Pages which have been removed from a Leitz notebook labeled "Aphorismen und Epigramme (in Verse)" are a mixture of original typescripts and carbons with h. corrections. Although many items are dated, the pages are not arranged in chronological order. One section in folder 12 has been numbered pp. 1-114, with items individually hand-numbered from 906-1179, many items designated as "Tagebuch" entries, predominantly dated 1930-1933.
      - 244 pages, 1930-1938 (Box 7 (3.1.4-Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose), Folder 45)
      - 249 pages, 1930-1938 (Box 7 (3.1.4-Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose), Folder 46)
      - 244 pages, 1930-1938 (Box 7 (3.1.4-Poems, aphorisms, epigrams, short prose), Folder 47)
    - Aphorisms and lyrics, 1932-1935 (Box 8 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1)
      Including the aphorism collection entitled "Die Lebenslehre" (14p.). Typescript cc. 196p.
    - Aphorisms and short prose, 1933-1935; 266p (Box 8 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 2)
    - Poetry, aphorisms, short prose. Dated Kampen, 1938 July-1938 August (Box 8 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 3)
      Stapled in 3 sections. 8p., 14p., 30p. Typescript cc.
    - Poetry, 1937; 1940; Undated (Box 8 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 4)
      Pages were removed from a Leitz notebook labeled "Leitz IV" and are hand-numbered 1-316. Pages are a mixture of original typescripts and carbons with h. corrections. Also one original Ms. 1p. Although many items are dated, the pages are not arranged in chronological order.
    - Collection of 477 poems from which the author made selections, Undated primarily pre-1938 (Box 8 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 5)
      Each page is marked "yb" in upper right corner. None of the poems selected for the Abzieh-Bilderbuch are included in this selection. Typescript cc. 291p.
      Arranged alphabetically.
    - "Abzieh - Bilderbuch", [1940]; 3.1.10 (Box 8 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 6-14)
      - Collection of 206 poems, assembled from the author while en route to the United States via Japan, 1938-1940 (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 6)
        Typescript cc. ii, 69 [hand-numbered], 55p. Duplicate pages. Typescript cc. 16p.
      - "Abzieh-Bilderbuch" (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 7)
        Re-arrangement of the original selection of poems, according to Barbara Bates, arrangement was suggested by Willy von Bodmershof, ca. 1950. Typescript with h. corr. by the author. 99p. Table of contents. Typescript with numerous h. corr. 2p.
      - "Abzieh-Bilderbuch" (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 8)
        2 additional complete copies of Bodmershof arrangement. Pc., 99p. ea. Table of contents, with attached note containing comments from Barbara Bates. Pc. 2c. 2p. ea.
      - "Abzieh-Bilderbuch" (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 9)
        2 additional incomplete copies of the Bodmershof arrangement, accompanied by h. note slips (by Barbara Bates). Pc. 99p., 2p. Notes. Autograph 8p.
      - "Abzieh-Bilderbuch" (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 10)
        Pc. of a later typescript, in which the author's corrections (see folder 20) have been incorporated. 2c. 99p. ea. Table of contents, also corrected. Pc. 2c. 2p. ea.
      - "Abzieh-Bilderbuch", ca. 1972 (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 11)
        Original Typescript with title page containing the comment "Edited by Harry Zohn".
        Poem selection is identical to earlier versions, except that poems have been typed one to a page. Pages are identified with "AB" in upper right corner. Typescript 208p. Table of contents. Typescript 3p.
      - "Abzieh-Bilderbuch" (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 12)
        Pc. of Harry Zohn typescript. 208p. Table of contents. Pc. 3p.
      - "Abzieh-Bilderbuch", ca. 1977 (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 13)
        Original Typescript with title page containing the comment "Copyright: Barbara B. Bates".
        Poems have been typed one per page, however pages have been numbered in upper left hand corner based on the Bodmershof arrangement AB 1 - AB 99. 208p. Alphabetical table of contents. Typescript with h. corr. (B.B.). 6p.
      - Small black alligator notebook, containing poems and notes in German, many dated "Kobe 1939", Undated (Box 8 (3.1.10-"Abzieh - Bilderbuch"), Folder 14)
        also later entries in English.
    - "Tokyo poems", February-November 1940; 3.1.11 (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1-15)
      Manuscripts and typescripts of individual poems written in Tokyo.
      - "Tokyo poems", Undated (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 1)
        Author's handwritten listing of poems and epigrammatic verse, arranged by date, with first line of text. 4 separate listings. Autograph 8p.
      - Poems, February-May 1940; 60p (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 2)
      - Poems, June 1940 (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 3)
        Autograph 72p. Typescript 3p.
      - Poems, July 1940 (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 4)
        Autograph 72p. Typescript 48p. Typescript cc. 23p. Also 2 pencil sketches, accompanying the poem "Das Glück" (dated July 24, 1940).
      - Poems, August 1940 (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 5)
        Typescript 114p. Typescript cc. 35p.
      - Poems, September-November 1940 (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 6)
        Autograph 97p. Typescript 41p. Typescript cc. 30p.
      - "Tokyo poems", Undated; 94p (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 7)
        Photocopies of early typescripts of a selection of poems.
      - "Tokyo poems", February-May 1940 (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 8)
        Uncorrected carbon copies of typescripts of early Tokyo poems. 2c. 27p. ea.
      - "Tokyo poems", primarily June-September 1940; typescripts (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 9)
        Typescripts with corrections, as well as some notes attached with comments (by Barbara Bates). Some poems are hand-dated, and pages are hand-numbered in upper right corner with the designation "pb". Poems, often typed several to a page, are arranged alphabetically by the title of first poem on the page. Typescript 142p. Also handwritten alphabetical listing (by Barbara Bates) entitled "Pink Box sent Mireille". 5p.
      - "Tokyo poems", Undated (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 10)
        Carbons of typescripts in folder 37, also arranged alphabetically. Typescript cc. 142p.
      - "Tokyo poems", Undated (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 11)
        Carbons of typescripts in folder 37, random arrangement. Typescript cc. 142p.
      - "Tokyo poems", Undated (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 12)
        Carbon copies of typescripts, some with minor corrections.
        Poems are typed one to a page and date primarily from September-October 1940. Typescript cc. 116p.
      - "Tokyo poems", dating primarily July-August 1940 (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 13)
        Selection of 94 poems made by the author in 1972.
        Selection includes typescripts and carbons and multiple copies of the same poem. Typescript and cc. 192p. Also contains a 1-page table of contents, with handwritten notes (by Barbara Bates) concerning the selection of poems. Handwritten notes (by Barbara Bates) are also attached to many of the poems noting discrepancies between the typed and manuscript versions.
      - "Tokyo poems", 1972; photocopies (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 14)
        Selection of 94 poems by the author.
        Rearrangement by Barbara Bates, in alphabetical order and hand-numbered in upper right corner. Pc. 99p. Attached to many of the poems are typewritten copies of the handwritten notes (folder 1) by Barbara Bates. Alphabetical listing of poem titles. 2 versions. Pc. 1p. ea.
      - "Tokyo poems", ca. 1977 (Box 9 (3.1.11-"Tokyo poems"), Folder 15)
        Retyped selection of 94 poems. Coded and numbered in upper right-hand corner, T1-T105. Typescript and pc. 106p. Alphabetical title listing. 2c. 1p. ea. Notes on variations in typescripts. Typescript 2c. 6p. ea.
    - Poem in German, dated New York, 7 September 1941; 1p (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 16)
    - Poetry in English, 1943-1945; Undated (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 17)
      Manuscripts and typescripts of poems, predominantly from 1945. Includes several translations of poems from German into English. Autograph 7p. Typescript with h. corr. 48p.
    - Poetry in English, 1947; Undated (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 18)
      Autograph 6p. Typescript 15p.
    - Song lyrics, Undated (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 19)
      Typescript and cc. of lyrics to 16 original songs, some variant versions. Several dated 1949. Autograph 2p. Typescript with h. corr. and cc. 79p.
    - Original song lyrics, submitted by Bates to The National Five Arts Award as entries in a song-writing contest, 1949 (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 20)
      Typescripts of 16 songs. Typescript 23p.
    - Poetry in English, 1951-1952 (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 21)
      Typescripts and carbons of poems, most dated, some with variant versions, duplicates. Notes on some of the poems indicate they are transliterations of earlier German poems. Typescript and cc. 78p.
    - Original typescripts of poems submitted to Furioso (Carlton College) for publication, 1951-1952; 32p (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 22)
    - "Einsätze". Collection of 318 aphorisms in German, Undated; 3.1.19 (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 23-26)
      - "Einsätze" (Box 9 (3.1.19-"Einsätze". Collection of 318 aphorisms in German), Folder 23)
        Items indicated with a red "x" in the margin were published in Neue Schweizer Rundschau in 1951. Typescript with some h. corr. 28p. Notes concerning publication. Typescript 1p.
      - "Einsätze" (Box 9 (3.1.19-"Einsätze". Collection of 318 aphorisms in German), Folder 24)
        Photocopies of original typescript. 3c. 28p. ea.
      - "Einsätze", ca. 1977; retyped version (Box 9 (3.1.19-"Einsätze". Collection of 318 aphorisms in German), Folder 25)
        2 copies. Typescript and pc. 30p. ea.
      - "Einsätze" (Box 9 (3.1.19-"Einsätze". Collection of 318 aphorisms in German), Folder 26)
        15 aphorisms from the original collection, retyped one to a page, some with multiple copies. Typescript, cc. and pc.
    - "Monogriphs/Pebbles", Undated; 3.1.20 (Box 9 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 27-29)
      Collection of aphorisms in English, many based on the earlier German "Einsätze".
      - "Monogriphs/Pebbles" (Box 9 (3.1.20-"Monogriphs/Pebbles"), Folder 27)
        Several versions. Typescript with numerous h. corr. 10p. Another version. 2c. Typescript with h. corr., cc. 6p. ea.
      - "Monogriphs" (Box 9 (3.1.20-"Monogriphs/Pebbles"), Folder 28)
        Collection of 151 aphorisms in English, many transliterations of the German "Einsätze". 1951. 2 copies. Typescript and cc. 14p. ea. Copies of originals. Pc. 3c. 14p. ea.
      - "Monogriphs" (Box 9 (3.1.20-"Monogriphs/Pebbles"), Folder 29)
        Collection of aphorisms, typed one to a page. Typescript with notes on the table of contents page concerning the categories of aphorisms. Dated 6/10/57 and 10-16-60. 113p.
    - "Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von Bodmershof, ca. 1950; 3.1.21 (Box 10 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 1-7)
      132 poems, arranged into 7 sections (I. Metaphysisches und Religiöses; II. Liebe und Freundschaft; III. Reisen; IV. Ferner Osten; V. Heiteres; VI. Bizarres; VII. Ausklang).
      - "Gedichte" (Box 10 (3.1.21-"Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von), Folder 1)
        Typescript with h. corr. 163p. Some carbons have been substituted for originals. Table of contents. Typescript with h. corr. 3p. Also several h. notes (from Barbara Bates) referring to changes from original versions.
      - "Gedichte", 163p (Box 10 (3.1.21-"Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von), Folder 2)
        Photocopies of original Bodmershof arrangement.
      - "Gedichte", 16p (Box 10 (3.1.21-"Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von), Folder 3)
        Photocopies of original Bodmershof arrangement, (Handwritten notes differ from those in the copy above).
      - "Gedichte", 24p (Box 10 (3.1.21-"Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von), Folder 4)
        "Gedichte". Pc. of poems, accompanied by the note (in handwriting of Barbara Bates) "Not used by Bodmershof in Gedichte".
      - "Gedichte", Undated (Box 10 (3.1.21-"Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von), Folder 5)
        Retyped version of Bodmershof arrangement. Typescript xii, 178p.
      - "Gedichte", ca. 1977; retyped version (Box 10 (3.1.21-"Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von), Folder 6)
        Pages numbered and coded G-1 to G-193 in upper right-hand corner.
      - "Gedichte", 193p (Box 10 (3.1.21-"Gedichte". Arrangement of poems made by Willy von), Folder 7)
        "Gedichte". Pc. of 1977 version.
    - "Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams selected by the author from his earlier writings. In German, pre-1940; 3.1.22 (Box 10 (3-Manuscripts and Typescripts), Folder 8-13)
      Collection of 258 verse epigrams selected by the author from his earlier writings. In German.
      - "Versepigramme: 2 Hefte, S. 1-53 und S. 54-91" (Box 10 (3.1.22-"Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams ), Folder 8)
        Original typescripts. "Epigramme I". 158 poems. Typescript with author's h. corr. 53p. "Versepigramme II". 100 poems. Typescript with author's h. corr. 38p. Table of contents. Pc. 5p.
      - "Versepigramme I & II" (Box 10 (3.1.22-"Versepigramme". Collection of 258 verse epigrams ), Folder 9)